<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Archives on Alex Griffin</title><link>https://ajgrf.com/post/</link><description>Recent content in Archives on Alex Griffin</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ajgrf.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Defining Shell Aliases for Subcommands</title><link>https://ajgrf.com/post/shell-subaliases/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ajgrf.com/post/shell-subaliases/</guid><description>&lt;p>
If you spend any time using the command line, you&amp;#39;re probably familiar
with aliases. The idea is to substitute a short and easy name for
frequently-typed or long commands. For example, the following common
alias lets you shorten &lt;code class="verbatim">ls -la&lt;/code> to just &lt;code class="verbatim">ll&lt;/code>:&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="src src-sh">
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre class="chroma">&lt;code class="language-sh" data-lang="sh">&lt;span class="nb">alias&lt;/span> &lt;span class="nv">ll&lt;/span>&lt;span class="o">=&lt;/span>&lt;span class="s1">&amp;#39;ls -la&amp;#39;&lt;/span>&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>
Some commands, like &lt;code class="verbatim">git&lt;/code>, provide hierarchical subcommands. To view the
status of a git repository, you run &lt;code class="verbatim">git status&lt;/code>, where &lt;code class="verbatim">git&lt;/code> is the
command your shell executes and &lt;code class="verbatim">status&lt;/code> is the subcommand interpreted
by Git. Git also provides an alias feature very much like shell aliases.
The command &lt;code class="verbatim">git config --global alias.st status&lt;/code> defines an alias &lt;code class="verbatim">st&lt;/code>
for the &lt;code class="verbatim">status&lt;/code> subcommand, so that you only need to type &lt;code class="verbatim">git st&lt;/code>.
What if you could define new subcommands like that anywhere you wanted?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Automating Hyper Light Drifter's 800 Dash Challenge on the Nintendo Switch</title><link>https://ajgrf.com/post/hyper-light-dasher/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ajgrf.com/post/hyper-light-dasher/</guid><description>&lt;p>
I do all of my gaming these days on a Nintendo Switch (with the
exception of &lt;a href="http://www.zachtronics.com/">Zachtronics&lt;/a> games on my
Linux machine). Lately I&amp;#39;ve been playing
&lt;a href="https://heartmachine.com/hyper-light">Hyper Light Drifter&lt;/a>, a gorgeous
retro-styled action adventure game that its creator calls a mix of 2D
Zelda and Diablo. The game is challenging, but plays nearly perfectly.
Except…&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
There is one optional challenge which calls for you to dash 800 times
consecutively in a confined space. This requires you to button mash with
precise timing while directing the character in a circle to avoid
bumping into any walls. It&amp;#39;s brutal, and
&lt;a href="https://old.reddit.com/r/hyperlightdrifter/">discussion spaces&lt;/a> related to
the game are filled with stories and complaints about this challenge.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
After many failed attempts and probably tens of thousands of button
mashes later, I decided there was probably a better way. On the PC
version, many players have decided to simply cheese the game by abusing
the keyboard controls or even using a program to automate the entire
feat. Doing this on the Switch is a bit trickier, though.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How to Set Up Dynamic DNS with OpenWrt and Gandi LiveDNS</title><link>https://ajgrf.com/post/openwrt-ddns-gandi/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ajgrf.com/post/openwrt-ddns-gandi/</guid><description>&lt;p>
&lt;a href="https://openwrt.org/">OpenWrt&lt;/a> supports quite a few dynamic DNS
providers in its very nice ddns-scripts package. Many of them are free,
but if you already pay for a domain name and DNS hosting at
&lt;a href="https://www.gandi.net/en">Gandi.net&lt;/a> why not just use that?
Unfortunately Gandi is not a supported provider, but it&amp;#39;s fairly
straightforward to get it working with a custom update script.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>